(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T22:06:52.532892",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Yeah!
One, two, check, check, check, check, your mic
We show, clown we show
Uh, huh
Yeah, ha-ha!
Come on, come on, yo! Uh!
No doubt yo, no doubt yo,
no doubt yo!
This is Zeebra, yeah.
Hot show, oh, Dragon Ash show!
Come on, come on, yeah.
Oh, let's go, yo!
Turn up the radio そう今日も聞こえるよ
Turn up the radio, yes, I can hear it again today,
風に揺られ流れる stereo
The stereo flowing, swayed by the wind,
肩で刻む軽快な rhythm
The rhythmic beat carved by my shoulders,
想いをのっけて届けるよ rhyme
I'll put my feelings into this rhyme and deliver it,
よく晴れた空の真下
Right under the clear, sunny sky,
僕らは遥かな未来目指しました
We aimed for a distant future,
master key 握り締め出発
Grip the master key and depart,
雑踏の中 kick down 一発
Kick down once in the middle of the crowd.
今想う闘いの日々
Thinking about the days of struggle now,
感謝するごとに溢れ出す慈悲
Compassion overflows every time I feel gratitude,
しのぎを削ったあの攻防戦
That defensive battle where we sharpened our skills,
今なお続くここは最前線
This is still the front line.
父から得た揺るぎない誇り
The unwavering pride I got from my father,
母がくれた大きないたわり
The great compassion my mother gave me,
キミにもらう温かいぬくもり
The warm tenderness I receive from you,
明日への糧に生き抜くために
To live and survive as food for tomorrow.
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yeah yeah yo!
俺は東京生まれHIP HOP育ち
I was born in Tokyo, raised on hip hop
悪そうなやつは大体友達
People who seem bad are mostly friends
悪そうなやつと大体同じ
Mostly the same as bad-looking people
裏の道歩き見てきたこの街
Walking the back alleys, watching this city
渋谷 六本木 そう思春期も早々に
Shibuya, Roppongi, my adolescence early on
これにぞっこんに
I was hooked on this
カバンなら置き放してきた高校に
I left my school bag at high school
マジ親に迷惑かけた本当に
I really caused trouble for my parents
だが時は経ち今じゃ雑誌のカバー
But time passed, now I'm on a magazine cover
そこらじゅうで幅きかすDON DADA
Don dada making its presence felt everywhere
マイク掴んだらマジでNo.1
Once I grab the mic, I'm seriously No.1
東京代表トップランカーだ
Tokyo representative, top ranker
そうこの地この国に生を授かり
Born in this land, in this country
Jahに無敵のマイク預かり
Given the invincible mic by Jah
仲間たち親たちファンたちに今日も
To my friends, parents, fans today too
感謝して進む荒れたオフロード
I proceed with gratitude, on the rough off-road
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when the sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yeah, mic check one, two, uh
日出ずる国に僕ら生まれ育ち
Born and raised in the land of the rising sun
今こうして踏みしめる大地
The earth we are treading on now like this
常に開く新しいPage
Always opening a new page
旅に出ようそれぞれのStage
Let's go on a journey, to each our own stage
ここに綴る喜びと感謝
Joy and gratitude spelled out here
共に奏でる真の理解者
True confidants playing together
つつみ隠さず時代を描写
Describing the era without hiding it
Pressureはねのけて乱反射
Pushing away the pressure, diffuse reflection
注ぎ込もう溢れ出す感情
Pouring out overflowing emotions
いつの日にも絶やさない愛情
Love that will never fade on any day
ひるむことなく飛び込む戦場
A battlefield to dive into without hesitation
枯れることなく咲く百合の紋章
The emblem of the lily blooming without withering
やさしい風ぬける昼下がり
The afternoon when a gentle breeze blows
虹がのぞいたこんな雨上がり
This rainy day after which a rainbow appeared
陽の光映した水たまり
Puddle reflecting the sunlight
日々の喜びここに賛美
Praise for the joy of daily life here
この胸の高鳴りを
I carry this heart-pounding
歌にのせて
Into the song
日々ここにあるもの
The things that are here every day
この手に感じて
Feeling them in my hands
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when the sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
ルパン
Lupin!
ルパン！
ルパン三世
[Title: Lupin III]
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
[Song: Lupin The Fire]
let me show your my everything
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Look at this fantasy of dreams
今こそ走る時なんだ
It's time to run now
It's show time
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me from there, a one-man show
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
A trial like this isn't enough
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
It's not things that I want
I steal your heart
Listen! Party people!
僕は人生駆け上がる猛スピード
I run up through life at full speed
まるでスキーの直滑降
Just like skiing straight downhill
核弾頭
Like a nuclear warhead
決めたことには頑固
Stubborn about the things I decide
ゆっくり生きる術なんて知らない
I don't know how to live slowly
ここんステージ遠慮はいらない
No need to be reserved on this stage
やることはやりますわ
I'll do what I have to do
高みの山目指せ
Aim for the mountain peak
Put your hands up in the air!
それを見つめる君はセクシー
You, watching me, are sexy
甘くとろけるまるでチェルシー
Sweet and melting, just like Chelsea
手櫛で髪掻きあげる様
The way you push your hair up with your fingers
僕にとっての女王様
You are my queen
For me, you're my queen.
そんなあなたを今夜抱きしめる
Tonight I will hold you close,
and 熱い唇をいただく
and take your hot lips.
そして何よりも欲しいのよ
And above all, what I want is...
あなたの心 狂おしいほど
your heart, so much that it drives me crazy.
It's a party night
Dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance
Everybody, don't stop dancing.
Let's go just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even if it's a thorny path,
凍てつく夜だろうが
Even if it's a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ 君と二人で
Impossibilities will become possible, with just the two of us.
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
だから そう だから
So, yes, that's why...
誰も手にしたことないお宝もらう
I'll take the treasure that no one has ever laid hands on.
狙った獲物は逃がさない
I'll never let my target get away.
それがなんだろうと大泥棒
No matter what it is, I'm a master thief.
先の先まで計算たてて<
Calculating steps far, far ahead,
瞬時にひらめく名案
A brilliant idea flashes in an instant.
そして「あっ!」と思ったらもう居ない
And just when you think "Oh!", I'm already gone.
もはや芸術ばりの盗みの美学
A theft aesthetic that is practically an art form.
Put your hands up in the air!
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Feast your eyes on this dream-like fantasy.
今こそ走る時なんだ (it's show time)
Now is the time to run! (It's show time!)
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Just watch from there, my one-man show.
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
An ordeal like this isn't nearly enough.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't a mere object...
i steal your heart
絶対に逃がさん！
I definitely won't let you get away!
無駄な抵抗はやめておとなしくお縄につきな ルパン！逃がさんぞー！
Stop your futile resistance and surrender quietly, Lupin! I won't let you escape!
誰かが居ないと張り合いがない
If there's no one around, there's no rivalry.
相手が居てこそ間違いない
Having an opponent is definitely key.
身近にゃ素敵なライバル
A wonderful rival close by,
競い合い互いにハイになる
competing and raising the stakes for each other.
ファイナルステージだ 天王山
It's the final stage, the deciding match.
お前と勝負の演奏さ
A showdown performance with you.
マジで今夜はサシで
Seriously, tonight it's one-on-one,
どっちが勝っても文句はナシで
and whoever wins, there'll be no complaints.
Put your hands up in the air!
ワルサー使いこなす僕はワルさ
Handling my Walther, I'm bad news.
曲がったこと嫌いプラスアルファ
I hate injustice, and plus some,
ラップマスター ジェダイも目じゃない
A rap master, even Jedi can't compete.
しかし可愛い女にも目がない
But I also have a weakness for pretty girls.
Oh baby それは演技? or 本気?
Oh baby, is that an act? Or are you serious?
僕は君に一本気
I'm totally devoted to you.
一本道走り続けます
I'll keep running down this single path,
空へ飛ばす今日から明日
flying up to the sky, from today to tomorrow!
It's a party night
Dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance
Everybody, don't stop dancing.
Let's go just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even if it's a thorny path,
凍てつく夜だろうが
Even if it's a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ 君と二人で
Impossibilities will become possible, with just the two of us.
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Feast your eyes on this dream-like fantasy.
今こそ走る時なんだ (it's show time)
Now is the time to run! (It's show time!)
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Just watch from there, my one-man show.
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
An ordeal like this isn't nearly enough.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't a mere object...
あなたのハート
...it's your heart!
愛すべき仲間や家族がいる
I have my beloved friends and family,
信念やプライドを曲げずに貫くべし！
And I must stay true to my beliefs and pride!
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
Let me show you my everything
眩しい眼差しをうけて
Basking in your dazzling gaze,
君のために今日を捨てるよ (it's show time)
For you, I will throw away today. (It's show time!)
世界で一人の最愛の
To my one and only beloved in the world,
君自身に気持ち伝えたいよ
I want to convey my feelings to you directly.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't a mere object...
あなたのハート
...it's your heart!
普段はとぼけた三枚目
Usually a goofy comic relief,
やる時ゃ誰より真剣で
But when the time comes, more serious than anyone.
頼りになるいざという時
Reliable when it really counts.
こうなりたい誰が見ても素敵
I want to be like that—stunning to everyone who watches.
知性備えたスーパーマン
A Superman equipped with intellect,
横にはお決まりスーパーウーマン
And by his side, the usual Superwoman.
残り二小節ラストスパート
The final spurt with two bars left,
憧れの男 lupin the third
The man of our admiration, Lupin the Third!
獲物は確かにいただいたぜ
I have indeed taken the prize!
はい！ということで 「Grateful Days」と「ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー」 2曲続けて聴いていただきました！
Yes! And with that, you heard "Grateful Days" and "Lupin the Fire," two songs back-to-back!
「Grateful Days」はですね ええと 男性二人と女性一人の曲なんですけど
Now, "Grateful Days" is a song for two males and one female,
女性のところはね 絶対アズちゃんが良いってことでアズちゃん で
and for the female part, I absolutely wanted Azu-chan, so Azu-chan was a must. And...
ラップパートはもう ノエルちゃんの顔しか浮かばなかったので ノエルちゃんにお願いしました 二人ともありがとう！
for the rap part, only Noel-chan's face came to mind, so I asked her. Thank you both!
でね ルパンの映像が流れてみんなびっくりしたんじゃない？ ころねもびっくりした
And that Lupin footage playing, weren't you all surprised? Korone was surprised, too!
で 今日のハッシュタグは もうね 7周年だって すごいよね
And as for today's hashtag, it's our 7th anniversary already, which is amazing, right?
この上のハッシュタグ「#戌神ころね7周年」で ぜひいっぱい呟いてください
Please tweet a lot using the hashtag above, "#InugamiKorone7thAnniversary"!
スクショも大丈夫だよ
Taking screenshots is totally fine, too.
ね ここのステージ なんか今日は違った感じだけど ここはどこなんでしょうか どこ？
You know, this stage... feels a bit different today. Where exactly are we? Where?
「INU VALLEY」！素敵 今日はイヌバレーから
"INU VALLEY"! Awesome! Today, from Inu Valley...
えー すべてお送りしますので よろしくお願いします
...we'll be broadcasting everything, so please enjoy!
って思っただけのさ なんか 画面小さくない？ って思ったよね リスナーさん ね
But, you know, didn't you listeners think, "Wait, isn't the screen a bit small?" Right?
ころねもちょっと思ったので ちょっとね あ ちょっと待って！
Korone thought so, too, so I'll... Ah, wait!
なんか 字が寄ってる！字が寄ってる！ やめて！やばい！やばい！回収になっちゃうよ これ！
Wait, the text is shrinking! The text is closing in! Stop! Oh no! Oh no! I'm going to get crushed by the screen!
ちょっと押して 今は令和なのでね 画面を広く使いたいので
Let me push it back. We're in the Reiwa era now, so I want a widescreen format!
あっち行け！
Go away!
もうちょっとあっち行け！
Go away a bit more!
もうちょっと！
Just a bit more!
オッケー オッケー こっちは？
Okay, okay. What about this side?
あっち行け！
Go away!
え？そんなにころねと居たいの？ おいで
What? Do you want to stay with Korone that much? Come here.
あはは 本当に来るんじゃねえよ！ 本当に来るんじゃねえ！
Ahaha! Don't actually come over! Don't actually come!
いってよ、早く！
Go on, hurry!
行った？
Did it go?
あ、行ったね。なんだったんだろうね。
Ah, it went. I wonder what that was.
ということで、あ！なんか
And with that... Oh! Something...
なんか落ちてきたよ！
Something fell!
花びらかな？これ。あっちから降ってきた？
Is this a petal? Did it fall from over there?
ちょっと行ってみよう！
Let's go check it out!
さくら
Sakura
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories...
君の声が戻ってくる
...and your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
When you parted your hair fluttering in the wind,
淡い香り戻ってくる
that fleeting scent comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, Hyururiira...
さくら散りだす 思い出す 意味なく
The cherry blossoms start to scatter, and I remember for no reason.
灯りだす あの頃また気になりだす
Lights turn on, and again I wonder about back then.
変わらない香り 景色 風
The unchanged scent, scenery, and wind...
違うのは君がいないだけ
The only thing different is that you're not here.
ここに立つと蘇る こみ上げる記憶 読み返す
When I stand here, it returns; memories well up, I read them over.
春風に舞う長い髪 たわいないことでまた騒いだり
Long hair fluttering in the spring wind, laughing over silly things again.
さくら木の真下 語り明かした
We talked all night under the cherry tree.
思い出は俺 輝いた証だ
Those memories are proof I shined.
さくら散る頃 出会い別れ
When cherry blossoms scatter, hellos and goodbyes.
それでもここだけは変わらぬままで
Yet this place remains unchanged.
咲かした芽 君離した手
The buds we bloomed, your hand I let go.
いつしか別れ交わしたね
Before we knew it, we parted ways.
さくら舞う季節に取り戻す
In the season of scattering cherry blossoms, I'll reclaim those days,
あの頃そして君呼び起こす
and bring you back.
花びら舞い散る
The petals scatter,
記憶舞い戻る
the memories scatter and return.
花びら舞い散る
The petals scatter,
記憶舞い戻る
the memories scatter and return.
気付けばまたこの季節で 君との想い出に誘われ
Before I knew it, this season returned, drawing me into memories of you.
心の扉叩いた でも手をすり抜けた花びら
I knocked on the door of my heart, but the petals slipped through my hands.
初めて分かった 俺若かった
For the first time I understood; I was young,
この場所来るまで分からなかったが
and didn't know until I came to this place.
此処だけは今も何故 定命のように香る風
Why does the wind still smell of destiny in this place alone?
暖かい日の光がこぼれる
The warm sunlight filters down.
目を閉じればあの日戻れる
When I close my eyes, I can return to that day.
いつしか君の面影は 消えてしまうよ 何処かへ
Before I knew it, your memory began to fade away somewhere.
あの日以来 景色変わらない
Since that day, the scenery hasn't changed.
散りゆく花びらは語らない
The scattering petals don't speak.
さくらの下に響いた君の声 今はもう...
Your voice that echoed beneath the cherry blossoms is now...
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories...
君の声が戻ってくる
...and your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
When you parted your hair fluttering in the wind,
淡い香り戻ってくる
that fleeting scent comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, Hyururiira...
そっと僕の肩に
Softly onto my shoulder,
舞い落ちたひとはらの花びら
a single petal fell.
手に取り 目をつむれば
When I take it in my hand and close my eyes,
君が傍にいる
you're by my side.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering cherry blossoms, forgotten memories...
君の声が戻ってくる
...and your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
When you parted your hair fluttering in the wind,
淡い香り戻ってくる
that fleeting scent comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, Hyururiira...
花びら舞い散る
The petals scatter,
記憶舞い戻る
the memories scatter and return.
花びら舞い散る
The petals scatter,
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Flower petals dance and scatter, memories dance and return.
花びら舞い散る
Flower petals dance and scatter...
人はこれって時にどうしても
People at times like this, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
say, "If only I could turn back time..."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, can't fix it, huh?
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been like that, well, it can't be helped, right?
きっと先は深くって不安定
Surely the future is deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but it's boring to just behave well, right?
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could get on a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler...
箱の中の猫を思っても
Even if I think about the cat in the box,
後悔だけが胸を焦がして
only regret burns my chest,
いつもあの猜疑心が遮るんだわ
and always, that suspicion blocks the way.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been like that, well, it can't be helped, right?
きっと先は深くって不安定
Surely the future is deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but it's boring to just behave well, right?
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could get on a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler...
どこをどうやってもね
No matter what I do,
時間ってのは戻せない
time cannot be turned back.
レンズ越し未来にめがけて
Aiming at the future through the lens,
ピースサイン伝えてる 今のところいい調子
I'm sending a peace sign, it's going well so far.
青春の1ページも
The first page of youth is just
たったの1ページで
one page,
自慢の人生のハイライトも
and even the highlight of my proud life
一夜きりのTweetのbuzzみたい
is like a one-night tweet that buzzes.
君と出会った日のことを覚えてるよ
I remember the day I met you.
イヤフォン垂らして この曲をきいていたよ
I was listening to this song with my earphones dangling.
あれから数えて今日は何年目！？
How many years has it been since then!?
今じゃ足跡どこも残るから これは歌詞カード
Now footprints remain everywhere, so this is a lyric card.
載せず鍵かけておこう ＃％＆＄”＝～
Don't upload it, keep it locked, #%&$”=~
ほらね、聴き取れない！！
See, you can't hear it!!
皆いつもくよくよくよ悩み
Everyone is always worrying and worrying,
締め切りに追われ歴史を作り
chased by deadlines, creating history.
弱さを無理やりごまかし
Forcing myself to hide my weakness,
君の芝生は緑 青じゃなくていい
your lawn is green, it doesn't have to be blue.
アイドル撮られちゃった真冬の空に
Idol taken, in the mid-winter sky,
政治家ぶれてブレちゃった帰り道
politicians wavering, wavering on the way home.
とうちゃんローン組んだ みはての先
Dad took out a loan to the unseen future,
でも時は全部を流して
but time washes everything away.
人はこれって時にどうしても
People at times like this, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
say, "If only I could turn back time..."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, can't fix it, huh?
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been like that, well, it can't be helped, right?
きっと先は深くって不安定
Surely the future is deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but it's boring to just behave well, right?
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could get on a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler...
俺ってやつはいつも気付いた時は手遅れ
I'm the type who always notices when it's too late.
絵空事ばかり うつつ抜かして
Just indulging in wishful thinking,
大事な人すら救えない
I can't even save important people.
だからこんな歌で自分に言い聞かせて
So I tell myself with a song like this.
あの時 あいつは多分気を使って
At that time, that person was probably being considerate,
とくに顔色変えず 何もないふり
especially with no change in expression, pretending nothing was wrong.
なんでいわないんだってムカついてもね
Even if I got angry, asking "Why don't you say it?",
やさしさからきてたなら しょうがないね
if it came from kindness, it can't be helped, right?
願わくばディスコで親父と母さんが会った日に行きたいね
I wish I could go to the day my dad and mom met at a disco.
後ろのジョックスに酒 かけて息子じきじきにチャンス作ってやるぜ
Pouring alcohol on the jocks in the back, I'll create a chance for my son directly.
どんなでかい時計だってすべてさ 始まりはこんな小さい歯車
No matter how big the clock is, everything begins with such a small gear.
細かいことはもういいや 疲れた
I don't care about the details anymore, I'm tired.
別に怒ってないってさ 未来は
I'm not angry, the future is...
人はこれって時にどうしても
People at times like this, no matter what,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
say, "If only I could turn back time..."
浅はかでも直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can fix it, can't fix it, huh?
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been like that, well, it can't be helped, right?
きっと先は深く不安定
Surely the future is deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but being well-behaved is just so boring, right?
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
Let's board the time machine,
トラベラーになれたら
and if I could become a traveler...
Done.
Yo
シボレーのドアを蹴り開けて 街に飛び出した俺たち
We kicked open the Chevy's doors and ran out into the streets.
暴力、酒に女、音楽 中指立てる大人の仮面に
Violence, booze, girls, and music—flipping off the masks of adults.
Oh さぁ踊ろう 「今日」という日を生き急ぐメンバー
Oh, let's dance, members rushing through this day called "today."
足りねえか？ Little louder! 欲望渦巻く路上が現場
Not enough? Little louder! The desire-swirling street is our stage.
Yeah いつだってそうだろ ブルーハーツ、尾崎、永ちゃんが教科書
Yeah, it's always been that way. Blue Hearts, Ozaki, and Yazawa are our textbooks.
くたばるまで格好つけて 誓ったよ あの放課後
Acting cool until we drop, we made a promise back then after school.
俺らピーターパン 「またいつか」なんて言っちゃいかん保存
We are Peter Pans, we must never say "someday again."
嘲笑っとる大人に言ってやる 人生はたったの一回だ
Let's tell those sneering adults: you only live once!
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in my chest, the primal urge.
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Pretending not to see? No, No.
夢追い笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, laughed at, scarred but shining on my way.
Go on! You should know who we are, Forever Young
Hey! Just next to me from now 大切なことは
Hey! Just next to me from now, the important thing...
魂の状態 Forever Young
...is the state of your soul. Forever Young.
Hey! It's your turn next time from here 「あの目始めれば良かった」
Hey! It's your turn next time from here. "I wish I had started that day."
その次の始めるべき時は今
The next best time to start is right now.
高笑いする都会の喧騒 ウケ狙いならば振り向けんぞ保存
The roaring laughter of the city's hustle, if you're just looking for laughs, we won't turn back.
何連呼？忘れろ？ 夢流した便所 見下ろしてきやがる摩天楼
What did you repeat? Forget it? The toilet where dreams were flushed, looking down is the skyscraper.
Oh まるで勝新みたく破天荒 伝説へとアテンド保存
Oh, wild and unprecedented like Shintaro Katsu, escorting us to a legend.
怖にゃあ怖にゃあてその程度 捨てろ負け惜しみ 過去の栄光
Scared, scared? Is that all you've got? Throw away your sore loser excuses and past glory.
永遠なんそはねぇて いつか天へ召され ペンで書き殴った
There's no such thing as eternity. Someday we'll ascend to heaven, written with a pen...
この魂は2PACみたく誰かの心を通過
...this soul, like 2PAC, will pass through someone's heart.
なぁ 何か忘れちゃねぇか 人生まるで映画 皆がエンターテイナー
Hey, haven't we forgotten something? Life is just like a movie, everyone is an entertainer.
思い出せ 思想は現実化する 誰がHighway飛ばすBentayga
Remember, thoughts become reality. Who's speeding down the highway in a Bentayga?
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in my chest, the primal urge.
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Pretending not to see? No, No.
夢追い笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, laughed at, scarred but shining on my way.
Go on! You should know who we are, Forever Young
Hey! 俺たちは今日だって 若気の至りのような
Hey! Even today, we...
夢を追いかけてきた Forever Young
...have been chasing dreams like youthful indiscretions. Forever Young.
Hey! 変わるはずなんてない さぁやってやろうぜ 今日は
Hey! There's no way we'll change. Come on, let's do this! Today...
残された人生で一番若い日だろ
...is the youngest day of our remaining lives, right?
半端な覚悟ならドブに捨てな 永遠
If you have half-hearted determination, throw it in the gutter. Eternity!
往生際が悪いってめぇ 笑い飛ばし 誇れ Better days
They say we don't know when to give up. Laugh it off and be proud of better days.
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで 永遠
It's not over yet. We won't let it end until we burn out. Eternity!
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで 永遠
It's not over yet. We won't let it end until we drop dead. Eternity!
Forever Young
もう夢を追いかけ 本気になった心は
The heart that chased dreams and became serious...
自分の指図も受けない Forever Young
...doesn't even take directions from itself. Forever Young.
Hey! その思いから逃れられないなら
Hey! If you can't escape from that feeling......
自ら向かうだけ
...then just go towards it yourself.
終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで 永遠
We won't let it end until we burn out. Eternity!
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで 永遠
It's not over yet. We won't let it end until we drop dead. Eternity!
まだ終わらない まだ終わらない Forever Young
It's not over yet! It's not over yet! Forever Young.
そう今日という日は お前に残された人生の一番若い日
Yes, today is the youngest day of your remaining life.
ふふふ
Fufu...
マリン、来てくれてありがとう！
Marine, thank you for coming!
呼んでくれてありがとう！イェーイ！
Thank you for inviting me! Yay!
いや、マジでこの「Forever Young」って曲をマリンと一緒に歌いたかったの。
Seriously, I really wanted to sing this song, "Forever Young," with you, Marine.
ああ、それはマリンがおばさんにならないように？
Oh, so that Marine won't turn into an old lady?
そう！もうForeverのYoungだって思ってるから！
Yeah! Because I think you're Forever Young!
そうだね、永遠にヤングだね！みんな、みんな！保存
That's right, forever young! Everyone, everyone!
悩む！
It's hard to decide!
うー。
Mmm...
でもマリン、今日はね、今日はね...
But Marine, today, you see...
え、後ろ見て？
Look behind you.
演奏してくれてる！
They're performing for us!
気まずいよ！
This is awkward!
今日はね、演奏してくれてるのみんなが。
Today, everyone is playing for us.
乗ってるよ。乗ってるよ。
They're grooving! They're grooving!
乗ってるでしょ？え、どの、どの人と写真撮りたい？
They're grooving, right? Which one do you want to take a picture with?
えー、そんな、一人だけみたいな、そんな、なんか...
Eh, just choosing one... That's kind of...
いやいや、二人選んでいい、二人選んでいい。
No, no, you can choose two! Choose two.
かわいそうじゃん、選ばれなかったら。
It'd be sad for the one not chosen.
二人選ぼう、二人選ぼう。
Let's choose two! Let's choose two.
俺もう、コロねスキがなんか...
I mean, the Koronesuki look kind of...
いいよ、マリンが選ぶんだよ。
It's fine, Marine will choose.
あ、マリンが選ぶ、あ、うん。
Ah, Marine will choose? Ah, okay.
どう？最初は...
How about... First is...
待って、映して、後ろ。
Wait, show them. The background.
みんな下向いて。
Everyone, look down.
細犬さん？
Hosoinu-san?
かわいい！かわいい！
So cute! So cute!
じゃあ細犬、まず細犬と写真撮ろっか。
Then, let's take a photo with Hosoinu first.
かわいいよ、細犬。こっちおいで、マリン、こっちにね。
He's cute, Hosoinu. Come here, Marine, this way.
はい、細犬でーす。えーと、細犬はギターかな？
Yes, it's Hosoinu. Um, is Hosoinu on guitar?
あ、ギターですか？細犬ちゃん。
Ah, are you playing the guitar, Hosoinu-chan?
ベロの色が...
The color of his tongue is...
乾いてる、ベロ。
His tongue is dry.
ベロ乾い、ちょっと、吸い出されてるんだけど、ベロの...
His tongue is dry... Wait, it's being sucked in...
あ、乾いてる。
Ah, it's dry.
うん、乾いてる。あんまり触らないでね。
Yeah, it's dry. Don't touch it too much.
ごめんね、いっぱい触って。
Sorry for touching you so much.
え、次、誰がいい？
Who's next?
かわいい。あと一人、あと一人。じゃあ、太犬？
Cute. One more, one more. Then... Futoinu?
太犬だね。
Futoinu, right?
はい、太犬はドラムです！かわいい！
Yes, Futoinu is on drums! So cute!
でかい！
He's huge!
どぅるどぅるどぅるどぅる...
Drum roll...
かわいいね。
So cute.
ベロの色がちょっと明るい。
His tongue is a bit brighter.
細犬より。
Than Hosoinu's.
撮った？みんな撮った？
Did you take it? Did everyone take it?
イェーイ！撮った？かわいい！
Yay! Did you take it? So cute!
オッケーだね。
We're good then.
うん、オッケー。
Yeah, okay.
え、じゃあ最後さ、二人でも撮ろうよ、二人でも。
Then at the end, let's take one with just the two of us too.
あ、そうだね、二人でも撮ろう、二人でも。
Ah, right, let's take one together too.
二人で、はい、ポーズ。
The two of us, okay, pose.
え？
Huh?
ちょっと...
Wait...
あ、ごめんごめん、やっぱりじゃあね...
Ah, sorry, sorry. After all...
じゃあね、やっぱり一人で撮りたいみたいだから。
It seems they want to take solo photos after all.
あ、やっぱりね。
Ah, as expected.
コロねスキだもんね。
Because they're Koronesuki.
撮りますか。
Shall we take one?
コロねスキ、ころさん好き？
Koronesuki, do you like Koro-san?
好き？ころさん好き？
Like me? Do you like Koro-san?
あ、よかった。え、マリンも好き？
Ah, good. Um, do you like Marine too?
間に入ろう。
Let's squeeze in.
なんでだよ！
Why?!
コロねスキなのにころさんの隣に立てない気分どう？
How does it feel to be a Koronesuki but not be able to stand next to Koro-san?
嬉しい？マリンが隣で。
Are you happy Marine is next to you?
嬉しくない？
Not happy?
本当は好きなんでしょ？
You actually like me, don't you?
おい！やめろ、やめろよ！
Hey! Stop it, stop it!
だめ、もうだめ、帰るよ。帰るよ、もう。
No, forget it, I'm going home. I'm leaving.
はい、帰ろう。はい、帰ろう。
Okay, let's go. Let's go.
はい、今日はね、このバンドメンバーがいましたけれど。
Yes, today we had these band members with us, but...
ええ。はい。
Yes. Right.
え、マリンとも最後に撮りたい。
Wait, I want to take a photo with Marine at the end too.
あ、撮ろう、撮ろう、撮ろう。せっかくね。
Ah, let's take it, let's take it. Since we're here.
フォーエバーヤングだから、今日は。
Because it's Forever Young today.
マイク、マイク！
Microphone, microphone!
マイク持って！マイク！
Hold the mic! Mic!
間違え、間違えちゃってるけどさ。
I got it wrong, I got it wrong, but...
マイクね。うん、いいよ、いいよ。
The mic, yeah, it's fine, it's fine.
でかい声で喋ると拾うから！
If you speak in a loud voice, it'll pick it up!
取れた？
Did we get it?
いけてる？
Is it working?
太犬！
Futoinu!
中心として。
As the center.
え、かわいく撮れたね。
Ah, it turned out cute.
ありがとう、マリン。
Thank you, Marine.
ありがとう。ね、ちょっと次の曲があるから行くけど。
Thank you. Hey, I have to go because of the next song, but...
あ、次の曲。うん。一人で帰れる？
Ah, the next song. Yeah. Can you go back alone?
おお、え、え、大丈夫？うん、大丈夫、大丈夫。
Oh, uh, is it okay? Yeah, I'm fine, I'm fine.
じゃあ、バンドメンバーのことよろしく。
Then, take care of the band members.
え？
Huh?
じゃあ、マリン、バイバーイ！
Well then, Marine, bye-bye!
え？よろしくって何？よろしくって...
Eh? What do you mean by take care of them?
え、どんな、何の曲？あ、え？
Wait, what, what song? Ah, eh?
あ、みんな！演奏して！みんな！次の曲だよ！
Ah, everyone! Play! Everyone! It's the next song!
らららー、おー、えい、えい、えい、えい
Lalala~ Oh, hey, hey, hey, hey
サボり方とか 甘え方とか
How to slack off, how to pamper myself,
逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
how to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えに来た 身につけて来た
I've finally started to learn, I've acquired them,
柔らかい頭
with a flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方
How to look cool, how to get carried away,
腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
how to steel my resolve, how to grow old gracefully.
脂乗りに乗った 濁った目した
With greasy, clouded eyes,
だらしない身体
and a sloppy body.
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や
How to be hated, how to be adored,
叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
how to scold, how to clash beautifully...
もっと覚えたい事が 山のようにある
There are mountains of things I still want to learn.
のびしろしかないわ
There's nothing but room to grow.
俺らまだのびしろしかないわ
We still have nothing but room to grow.
悪者扱いして きた街で
In the town where I was treated like a villain,
悪者扱いして きたオトナへ
to the adults who treated me like a villain.
変わりゆく俺、鏡の中へ
I'm changing, into the mirror,
尋ねても答えなら yeah yeah yeah
even if I ask, the answer is yeah yeah yeah.
去る者は追わない 引く底引いて
I won't chase those who leave, I'll step back when needed,
丸く収めたり 軽く受け流して
settling things smoothly, brushing them off lightly.
鏡の中で笑ってるお前
You're laughing in the mirror.
括れやしなかったわ。たったの三文字で
I couldn't bind myself with just three letters.
日々重くなる足取りで
With steps that grow heavier day by day,
自分の歩幅で闊歩してる
I'm striding at my own pace.
カマすとこカマす まかすとこまかす
Giving it my all when needed, letting go when I should,
割と適当な段取りで
with a rather casual plan.
やっと分かって来たかも
I think I finally understand...
このポンコツの操縦の仕方を
how to pilot this piece of junk.
19の時の「ついに来たか…」より
More than the "It's finally here..." when I was 19,
もっと清々しい気持ち
it's an even more refreshing feeling.
隅田川にかかる
Spanning the Sumida River...
勝鬨橋を渡る
I cross the Kachidoki Bridge.
左手にスカイツリー
With Skytree on my left...
右手に東京タワー 俺はその真ん中
and Tokyo Tower on my right, I'm right in the middle.
サボり方とか 甘え方とか
How to slack off, how to pamper myself,
逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
how to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えに来た 身につけて来た
I've finally started to learn, I've acquired them,
柔らかい頭
with a flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方
How to look cool...
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 いい年のこき方
How to look cool, act cocky, be resolute, and grow old gracefully
脂乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしない体
At my peak, with cloudy eyes and a sloppy body
幸せの体感速度は 早く成るばかり
My perceived speed of happiness only gets faster
傷が癒えていく速度は 遅く成るばかり
The speed at which wounds heal only gets slower
他人に期待をしないのが 今の俺の強み
Not expecting anything from others is my current strength
手負いでも進める距離なら 行く
If it's a distance I can cover even if wounded, I'll go
身の程を知る程に
The more I know my limits,
胸を張り いつも通り
the more I puff out my chest, as usual.
でも時にしたって良い背伸び
But sometimes it's okay to stretch beyond my limits,
やっと大人げないが出来る年
finally at an age where I can act immature.
小さな枠組み ただの数字
Small frameworks, just numbers,
縛られずに でも腹くくり
unbound by them, but still prepared.
あの日の俺が立ち止まる
The me from back then would freeze in his tracks...
ほどにデカくそびえ立つ
towering so high.
隅田川にかかる
Spanning across the Sumida River,
勝鬨橋を渡る
I cross the Kachidoki Bridge.
重なるスカイツリー
The overlapping Tokyo Skytree
東京タワーと真ん中の頼りない背中
and Tokyo Tower, with my unreliable back in the middle.
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to depend on others, how to run away, how to make excuses,
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
I've finally learned and acquired a flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 いい年のこき方
How to look cool, act cocky, be resolute, and grow old gracefully
脂乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしない体
At my peak, with cloudy eyes and a sloppy body
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be disliked, how to be adored, how to scold, and how to clash beautifully
覚えたいことが山のようにある
There's a mountain of things I want to learn.
のびしろしかないわ
I have nothing but room to grow!
Nothing but room to grow!
のびしろしかないわ
俺らまだのびしろしかないわ
We still have nothing but room to grow!
ばかまじめ
[Title: Bakamajime]
くだんない話と
With stupid stories,
うざったい貴様と
and an annoying you,
なみなみの毎日に 注がれてく
poured into these overflowing days.
怠いが溢れだしてく
Dullness keeps overflowing.
飯がまだ届かない
My food hasn't arrived yet,
仕事は片付かない
and my work won't be finished.
うだつの上がらない毎日にため息ばかり
Sighing every day at a life that won't get ahead.
でまたド派手にすっころび
Then I slip and fall spectacularly again,
洗い立てのシャツにこぼすコーヒー
spilling coffee on my freshly washed shirt.
前のめりその姿勢だけは褒めて良し
I'll praise you just for that forward-leaning posture.
肩落とす並木通り
On the tree-lined street where I drop my shoulders,
増えた柄と差し色に
with the patterns and accent colors that increased...
嗚呼 本当嫌になる毎日だ
Ah, it's really an annoying day.
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I did things I didn't want to do,
嫌々早起きしたって
even if I got up early unwillingly,
その分素敵な何かが
it's not like
訪れるとかそんなわけでもないのにさ
something wonderful is going to visit.
今日もまた頑張っちゃうよな
But I'll do my best again today,
がむしゃら以外知らないから
because I don't know anything but to struggle.
不器用で意地っ張りで
Clumsy and stubborn,
馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
good luck to us, who are foolishly serious.
重くなってきた荷物をちょっと置いて立ち止まり
Put down the heavy luggage a bit and stop.
昨日の事なんざ忘れちまえば同じ
It's the same if you just forget about yesterday.
浴びるday light 羽根伸ばし
Basking in the daylight, stretching my wings,
それか月夜にこっそりと吐き出してしまえば良い
or I should just secretly spit it out into the moonlight.
でもその前にアレとコレの話
But before that, the talk about this and that.
その為には先ずはソレを片し
For that, first, finish that.
って今何時？ いやその前に
Wait, what time is it now? No, before that...
今日もなんだかんだ騒がしい毎度あり
It's noisy one way or another today, thanks as always.
1ヶ月くらい何にも 考えずだらだらしていたいな
I want to be lazy for about a month without thinking about anything.
ゆっくり休んで遊んで眠っていたいなって
I want to rest, play, and sleep slowly...
思う日もあるけれど
Even if there are days when I think so,
やっとここまで来たんだよ ここじゃ終われないんだよ
I finally came this far, I can't end it here.
辛い きついもいつかは 笑い話にできると信じてるんだほら
Painful and tough, someday I believe we can turn it into a funny story, look!
今日もまた頑張っちゃうからさ
I'll do my best again today,
がむしゃらに愛を歌うからさ
because I'll sing of love with all my might.
目一杯吸い込んだ空気
I inhaled deeply...
あぁ 本当素晴らしい毎日だ
Ah, it's really a wonderful day.
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I did things I didn't want to do,
嫌々早起きしたって
even if I got up early unwillingly,
ほんの少しの幸せに
just by touching a little bit of happiness,
触れるだけで全部全部ありに思えるんだ
I can feel that everything, everything is alright.
明日もまた頑張ってみようか
Shall we try our best again tomorrow?
がむしゃらに生きていくんだ
We're going to live, struggling forward!
不器用で意地っ張りで
Clumsy and stubborn,
馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
good luck to us, who are foolishly serious.
do my thing do your thing
肩の力を抜いて柔軟に
loosen your shoulders and be flexible.
again do my thing do your thing
あと1ミリ背伸び
stretching just one more millimeter.
あぁ 本当嫌になっちゃうよな
Ah, it's really annoying...
それでも今を生きている
Even so, we are living in the present.
不器用で意地っ張りで
Clumsy and stubborn,
馬鹿真面目なあなたに幸あれ
good luck to you, who are foolishly serious.
Longiness
[Title: Longiness]
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
Even if you struggle wanting to be like him, you'll sink like you're in a bottomless swamp
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
Light a fire with NickelBurn
君の心に落とすimagination
And drop an imagination into your heart
ギリギリでフライできず地獄送りさ
Just barely unable to fly, sent straight to hell
君が飛べなかった理由を一つ教えたろうか
Shall I tell you one reason why you couldn't fly?
それは目の前のプロップスに心揺だね近道した結果
It's because you surrendered your heart to the props in front of you, taking a shortcut
誰かの後をつけてるだけだったからさ
And ended up just following behind someone else
未だわからないか最初は気づいてた
Don't you get it yet? You realized it at first
知らぬふりして自分の道だと言い聞かせた
But pretended not to know, convincing yourself it was your own path
他は騙せないオリジナルを奏でないと
You can't fool others unless you play an original tune
過去の自分に足を引っ張られて退場
Dragged down by your past self, exiting the stage
俺とお前との差は遺伝子レベル
The difference between me and you is at a genetic level
俺を狂わせた父母祖父母には感謝してる
I'm grateful to my parents and grandparents who drove me crazy
さらに磨き上げた自分自身にも感謝してる
And I'm grateful to myself for polishing it even further
なのになんかしてる君 差が離れてくうちに
Yet, you're doing whatever, while the gap keeps growing
絶望を感じどうせラップやめるよ
Feeling despair, you're gonna quit rap anyway
5年後いや4年後？これ。余命宣告
In five years, or maybe four? This is a prognosis
現状に満足して威張ってんの？
Are you acting big, satisfied with the status quo?
俺らは発展途上でもかっけぇぞ
We're still developing, but we're cool as hell
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
Even if you struggle wanting to be like him, you'll sink like you're in a bottomless swamp
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
Light a fire with NickelBurn
君の心に落とすimagination
And drop an imagination into your heart
恋焦がれた男達と時をかけた女達
The boys in love and the girls who leapt through time
上辺だけのお友達がお前のこと甘やかす
Superficial friends spoil you
命削りぬらりくらり情熱だけを注ぐ歌詞
Lyrics of life-squeezing, wandering about, pouring only passion
現実に泡濡らす理想たちが雨降らす
Idealisms that soak reality in bubbles make it rain
あれもカスでこれもカスで俺の歌詞で振り向かす
That is trash and this is trash, I'll make them turn around with my lyrics
フキになって無視したって知らぬうちに街を這う
Even if you turn your back and ignore it, it crawls through the town before you know it
体揺らし声を枯らしたって誰も聴いてない
Even if you shake your body and rasp your voice, no one is listening
導かれて聴いてみても耳は糸を引いてない
Even if they are guided to listen, their ears are not drawn to it
今日で明日明後日明後日も白紙の中あさって
Today, tomorrow, the day after, and even the day after that, searching in the blank space
思想すらも曲がってるだけど顔は笑ってる
Even your thoughts are twisted, but your face is smiling
嘘だらけの肥溜めで のぼせるまで浸かって
Soaking in a cesspool of lies until you get dizzy
天に祈り捧げたって変えられるのは声だけ
Even if you offer a prayer to heaven, the only thing you can change is your voice
何かあれば孤独気取りむしり取るかね
Acting lonely at the slightest thing, squeezing out money?
指で擦りめくり表あれば裏探すだけ
Rubbing and turning over with your fingers, if there's a front, you just search for the back
歯止め効かぬ無駄な愚痴も全て愛で砕けてる
Unstoppable, useless complaints are all crushed by love
もうこんな歌詞は書きたくない全部お前のせい
I don't want to write lyrics like this anymore, it's all your fault
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
Even if you struggle wanting to be like him, you'll sink like you're in a bottomless swamp
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
Light a fire with NickelBurn
君の心に落とすimagination
And drop an imagination into your heart
チ、チ、チーム友達
T-T-Team Friends
チーム友達
Team Friends
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
Who are we? Huh? Team Friends
関西 関東
Kansai, Kanto
西 東
West, East
北 南
North, South
チーム友達
Team Friends
チーム
Team
チーム友達
Team Friends
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
Who are we? Huh? Team Friends
お好み焼き 食う鶴橋
Eating okonomiyaki in Tsuruhashi
腹いっぱい
Stomach is full
飯は美味い
The food is delicious
一人じゃ寂しいし
It's lonely alone
電話来たり
So I get a call
かけ直したあと
After calling back
すぐ会いに行く
I go right away to see them
T-E-A-M T-O-M-O
D-A-C-H-I
TEAM TOMODACHI
T-E-A-M T-O-M-O
D-A-C-H-I
TEAM TOMODACHI
チーム友達
Team Friends
チーム友達 混ざり合い
Team Friends, mixing together
契り交わし飲んでる酒
Making a pact, drinking sake
契り
Pact
契ろう
Let's make a pact
契り
Pact
チーム友達
Team friends
チーム
Team
チーム友達
Team friends
チーム
Team
チーム友達
Team friends
俺たち何？
Who are we?
え？チーム友達
Huh? Team friends
チーム友達
Team friends
おーーー！ヨーヨーヨーヨー！
Ohhh! Yo yo yo yo!
かっこよくない？イェーイ！
Isn't this cool? Yeah!
うぃー、ミコちの顔、あ、ごめん、ミコちの顔よ
Whoa, look at Miko-chi's face. Ah, sorry, look at Miko-chi's face.
ふざけてんじゃない、おーい！
Stop messing around, hey!
ガラが悪いですよ
You look like a thug.
ちょっとね、この帽子とかのせいでね
Well, because of this cap and everything...
ちょっとヤカラっぽくなっちゃうけどね
we look a bit sketchy, don't we?
うん、かっこいいじゃん
Yeah, but it's cool!
でもみこ、こんな格好いつかしてみたかったんだよ！
But I've always wanted to dress like this!
これバチクソ高いから、これ気をつけて
This is insanely expensive, so be careful.
本当にね、今日来たら「これ用意してあるんで」って言われて
Really, when I arrived today, they said, "We have this ready for you."
「えっ？これ、何これ？」って
And I was like, "Wait, what is this?"
重たいでしょ？
It's heavy, right?
うん、重たい。でもかっこいい。
Yeah, it's heavy. But cool.
あの、ロックリーみたいになってるから今、うちら。
We're like Rock Lee right now, with these weights.
ロックリー！？
Rock Lee?!
おもり付けてるからね、今。
Since we're wearing training weights.
解き放たれたら、もっと動けるな。
Once we take them off, we'll move incredibly fast.
そうそうそう、外したらね、いい感じになりますけど。
Exactly, we'll be in top form once we remove them.
え、でも、ころさん、周年おめでとうございます！
But anyway, Koro-san, happy anniversary!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
もう、7周年だよ、ころね。
It's already your 7th anniversary, Korone.
ねえ！すごい！7年もだね！
I know! Amazing! 7 whole years!
え、待って、ミコちゃんの衣装見て？これ、誕生日で...
Wait, look at Miko-chan's outfit! This was for my birthday...
あ、着たやつね！
Ah, the one you wore!
かわいい！え、後ろも見せて、後ろも。
So cute! Show us the back, too.
今回用意してくれたこの装飾に、なんかマッチしてて嬉しくて。
It actually matches the decorations they prepared, so I'm happy.
めっちゃマッチしてます。
It matches perfectly.
え、でもそれで言うとさ、ころね、この衣装さ...
But speaking of which, Korone, this outfit...
ゲマズのイベントのやつじゃない？これ。
Isn't it from the Gamers event?
そうそうそう！超超超超ゲマズの衣装！
Yes, yes! The Cho Cho Cho Gamers outfit!
かわいいじゃん！
It's so cute!
ミコちゃん、今日ね、これが初お披露目んだ、この衣装の。
Miko-chan, today is actually the first debut of this outfit.
え！
What!
これで！
And with this!
これで「チーム友達」でちょっと初お披露目しちゃったんですけど。
We just debuted it while singing "Team Friends."
いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
That's awesome!
かわいい！ちょっと短くない？
It's cute! But isn't it a bit short?
あ、そう、ちょっとエッチじゃない？
Yeah, isn't it a bit lewd?
これめっちゃ短いんだよね、大丈夫？
It's really short. Is it okay?
お尻見えそう...
I can almost see your butt...
こら！見せるんじゃないよ！
Hey! Don't look at it!
大丈夫かな？
I hope it's okay.
しかもね、ころねなんかさ、めっちゃ胸がパツパツって言われてて、これ。
And also, they're saying Korone's chest is super tight in this.
いや、なんかちょっとシワができちゃってるもん、パツパツで。弾け飛びそうだよ、なんか。
Yeah, it's so tight there are wrinkles. It looks like it'll burst open.
多分ね、サイズが合ってないんだと思う。
I think the size is just wrong.
あ、でもそれぐらいがね、いいですからね。
Ah, but that tightness is actually perfect.
え、写真撮ろうよ、写真！
Let's take a photo! A photo!
写真撮りたい！
I wanna take a photo!
ちょっとアップめで撮りたいんだよな。
I want a close-up shot.
あ、いいじゃん、いいじゃん。
Oh, nice, nice.
じゃ、しゃがもう。
Let's crouch down.
しゃがむか。
Let's crouch.
ヨー！
Yo!
ヨー。
Yo.
あ、いいじゃん！
Oh, this is nice!
スパイダーマンみたいになってる。
We look like Spider-Man.
ヨー、ヨー！
Yo, yo!
え、じゃサングラスもさ、取ってさ。
Let's take off our sunglasses too.
あ、取るからね。
Ah, taking them off.
よいしょ、よいしょ。ちょっと待ってね、みんなね、よいしょ。
There we go. Wait a moment, everyone. There.
行くよ！せーの...
Here we go! Ready, set...
はい！
Cheese!
あ、いいじゃん！撮れた、撮れた。
Oh, nice! Got it, got it!
アップめで撮るじゃん。
Let's get a close-up.
アップめで撮りたい。イェーイ！
I want a close-up. Yay!
あ、じゃあちょっとカメラね、いただきましてね。
Let me grab the camera then.
あ、どう？
How's this?
イェーイ！
Yay!
ヨー！
Yo!
撮れてる？
Is it working?
チーム友達！
Team Friends!
ま、友達...
Well, friends...
どこ歌うの？
What part are you singing?
え、選んでくれたの嬉しかったよ。
But really, I was so happy you chose this song.
え、やっぱ「チーム友達」って言うぐらいの歌だから、
Well, since it's literally called "Team Friends,"
友達と歌いたくて。
I really wanted to sing it with a friend.
だから誰でもよかったんだけど、別に。
So honestly, anyone would have done, really.
友達だからみんな。
Since everyone is my friend.
おい！
Hey!
嘘、嘘、嘘！
Just kidding, kidding!
特に！特に！
Especially! Especially!
特にみこみこと歌いたかった。
I especially wanted to sing it with Miko-miko.
あ、チーム友達だからね、うちら。
Yeah, we are team friends, after all.
チーム友達、イェーイ！
Team Friends, yay!
え、でもそろそろね、次の曲なんじゃないですか？
But hey, isn't it about time for the next song?
あ、そう、もうちょっとね、もうちょっとだけ「つづくんじゃよ」なんだけど、
Oh, right. There's still a little bit left of "To be continued," but...
え、次どんな感じなの？
So, what's the next one like?
え、次はね...
Well, next is...
あの、パンツですね。
Um, pants.
え？
Huh?
パンツ。
Pants.
パンツ？
Pants?
恥ずかしい、やめて、撮らないで。
Embarrassing, stop it, don't film me.
待って、え？パンツって、この穿いてるパンツってこと？
Wait, what? Pants as in the ones we're wearing right now?
え、みこさん穿いてないの？
Wait, Miko-san, aren't you wearing any?
え？
Huh?
みこさん穿いてないの？パンツ。
Miko-san, aren't you wearing pants?
安心してください、穿いてますよ。
Don't worry, I'm wearing them!
穿いてる？
You are?
よかった、じゃあ。
Good, then.
ころねはまだこれからなのよ、パンツ。
For Korone, pants are coming up next.
え！穿いてないってこと！？
What! You mean you're not wearing any?!
ころねはちょっとこれからなの。
Korone's pants are coming up next.
これから。ごめんみこみこ、これからだから、ころねパンツ。
Coming up next. Sorry, Miko-miko, Korone's pants are next.
パ、パンツ...
P-Pants...
Don't worry, don't flex, Don't worry, don't flex
Don't worry, be naked
わ、穿いてる、パンツ
Wow, I'm wearing pants!
Animal naked
Nature naked
People naked
わ、穿いてる、パンツ
Wow, I'm wearing pants!
Don't worry, don't flex, Don't worry, don't flex
Don't worry, be naked
わ、穿いてる、パンツ
Wow, I'm wearing pants!
No pants, no fight
No pants, no sleep
No pants, no life
わ、穿いてる、パンツ
Wow, I'm wearing pants!
穿く、穿く、穿く、穿く、穿く、穿く、パンツ
Wear, wear, wear, wear, wear, wear pants!
穿く、穿く、穿く、穿く、穿く、穿く
Wear, wear, wear, wear, wear, wear
パンツ
Pants
neki king neki king neki neki king neki neki king neki king
Don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, don't flex, don't worry, be naked, bow wear it, pants
Animal, neki, nature, neki, people, neki, bow wear it, pants
You say neki, I say no, I say neki, you say no, you are wearing, I say pants, I say wearing, you say pants
neki king neki king neki neki king neki neki king neki king
Simon push, Simon push
I'm wearing pants, but I can post neki! Hey!
マフィオーサ
Mafiosa
Ah listen up
キラっと光る犬歯がお似合いの口が物語る
A mouth boasting shiny canine fangs tells a story,
リリカルがもくもくと充満し織り成すスモーキーなストーリー
of smoky lyrics that smolder and intertwine.
Let me see...
不確かな平穏と確かな不安を纏い彷徨う
Wandering clad in uncertain peace and certain anxiety,
お面じゃないことに恐れ慄く
trembling with fear that it is not a mask.
十色の価値観 騒ぐラジカル 何がはじまる? 不器用な生き様に心昏む
A spectrum of values, noisy radicals, what will begin? My heart dims at this clumsy way of life
I wonder why 理性を欠いたサバイブ 願っても願ってもなくならない
I wonder why... a survival devoid of reason, which won't go away no matter how much I wish.
I wonder why 危険度ハイなマイライフ Do it again, do it again
I wonder why... my life is high risk, do it again, do it again!
Chase chase, Where is my utopia こじ開ける扉 Viva 現状打破なら飛び乗りな
Chase, chase, where is my utopia? Prying open the door... Viva! If it's a breakthrough, jump on in!
くしゃくしゃの紙屑に傷ついたハート重ねる しわついたまま時を刻む
Layering a wounded heart onto crumpled paper scraps, carving out time while still wrinkled.
数多のお目目から逃げた Back in the day ひた隠しているファンキーなヘッド
Escaping from countless eyes back in the day, keeping my funky head hidden away.
個性の延長線上にあるギフトも誰かにとってはバグみたい
Even a gift on the extension of individuality seems like a bug to someone else.
伏し目を逸らし 行く当てもない
Averting my downcast eyes, with nowhere to go...
現状 感情 洗浄 出来ず立ち往生 抱いて
Stuck in a standstill, unable to wash away my current feelings, hold me...
泣いても足掻いても Fall... Fall... Fall... Fall...
Even if I cry or struggle, I fall, fall, fall, fall...
Uhhh... 放浪 噛み締め 揺蕩う
Uhhh... wandering, bearing down, swaying...
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far 一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
Hey don't panic, go too far, far, far! An animal taking one step forward.
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に
Step forward like a pro, way ahead, way ahead
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww Critical Critical Criti Criti
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww Don't panic, Go too far far far
暗闇が Take over さながら予定調和
Darkness takes over, just like a pre-established harmony.
覚えたての絶望にほだされ見る見る間に裏目を出す
Swayed by newly learned despair, things backfire in the blink of an eye.
手招く反逆のアイコン 一抹の不安抱くも迷走
Beckoning the icon of rebellion, harboring a touch of anxiety, yet straying.
平和ボケした連中を尻目に日陰練り歩けば Dope Dope Dope
Parading through the shade, ignoring the peace-addled crowd... Dope, dope, dope
What a uhmmm...
山積みトラブルに追い追われ多忙 やさぐれ肩側にはなむけ発砲
Chased by a mountain of trouble, busy as can be, a parting shot to my cynical side
Bang ba bang ba bang ba ぶち抜く不条理 ヘッドばんぱん
Bang-ba-bang-ba-bang-ba, blasting through the absurd, head-banging hard!
出る杭打つのに必死なプライド 塗れのエネミーに見舞う超ヤバイもん
Pride desperate to strike the nail that stands out, dealing something crazy to the filth-covered enemy.
狂った情緒で冷え切った体温 滾るこのエナジーは文字通りザイオン
Body temperature chilled by crazy emotions, this boiling energy is literally Zion!
運命捻じ曲げるトリガー 着火する煙たい Dogs の通りだ
A trigger that twists fate, passing through like smoking dogs on fire
皆誰もがスペシャルな存在ってこと忘れた結果
The result of everyone forgetting that they are a special existence.
自分と違う箇所否定して突っぱねる それこそ欠陥
Denying and rejecting what's different from yourself, that is the true flaw.
たくさんの矛盾と向き合い続けて尚 一向になくならない思かなる
Even as I continue to face countless contradictions, the lingering thoughts never fade
悲惨 失跡 闘争 Never never end
Tragedy, disappearance, conflict... Never, never end.
散らばる Hollow
Scattered Hollow...
ぎらり剥き出しの牙と思惑が絡み合う 消灯 深い夜と歌う
Glistening bared fangs and motives intertwine, lights out, singing with the deep night.
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far 一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
Hey don't panic, go too far, far, far! An animal taking one step forward.
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に
Step forward like a pro, way ahead, way ahead
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww Critical Critical Criti Criti
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww Don't panic, Go too far far far
Work like a dog 只管に磨いたジョブ
Work like a dog, a job polished through and through.
ぼんやり未来が望遠鏡に浮かんだ今日
A hazy future floated in the telescope today.
いつかのオメルタもスーベニア
The omerta of the past is also a souvenir.
凍り付いた心を溶かす My whereabouts
Melting my frozen heart... my whereabouts...
燃えやば
Burn up!
マフィオーサ 祝砲を放つ
Mafiosa, firing a celebratory salute.
アイネ・クライネ・ナハトムジーク ぐずった顔はグッバイ
Eine kleine Nachtmusik, goodbye to that grumpy face.
マフィオーサ 祝福の歌
Mafiosa, a song of blessing.
ようやく見つけた掛け替えのない居場所
I've finally found my irreplaceable place.
Say hoo! ほら一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Come on, let's dance together!
Say hoo! また一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together again!
Say hoo! ずっと一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together forever!
ようやく気付けたふたつとない居場所
I've finally realized this is my one and only place.
...居場所
...my one and only place.
みんな、マフィオーサ、ライブ初お披露目、どうだった？
Everyone! How was the live debut of MafiOSA?
ちょっと、パンツとマフィオーサで、2曲続けてだったんですけど、
I sang "Pants" and "MafiOSA" consecutively,
このね、パンツっていう曲めちゃめちゃ好きで、
and I really love this song called "Pants."
あの、ずっと暇な時めちゃめちゃ聴いてたので、今回歌えて嬉しいのと、
I used to listen to it all the time, so I'm happy to sing it,
ころねすきーにね、ピンクのパンツを穿いて踊ってもらえたのが、凄く楽しかったので、
and it was so much fun seeing Koronesuki wearing pink pants and dancing!
みんな踊ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you everyone for dancing!
はい、でね、今回、マフィオーサのライブ初お披露目をしたくて、
Yes, and this time, I wanted to debut MafiOSA live,
全部ね、ラップ曲でまとめてみたんですけど、
so I put together a set of all rap songs.
どうだったかな？
How was it?
ちょっと初めての試みだったから、すごいね、
It was a first-time attempt,
あの、準備段階から今日に至るまで、めっちゃドキドキで、
so I was really nervous from the preparation stage until today.
なんか、みんな楽しんでくれるかな、とか思ってたんだけど、
I was wondering if everyone would enjoy it...
だからね、みんなが楽しんで、ノリノリになってくれてたら嬉しいなと思います。
So, I hope you all enjoyed it and got into the groove!
でね、原曲知らないよって方がね、結構いると思うんですけど、結構はいないか。いると思うんですけど、
I think there are probably some who don't know the original songs,
もしね、そういう方はぜひ、めちゃめちゃカッコいいのでね、全部の曲。原曲ぜひ聞いてみてください。
but if so, please check them out, because all of the original songs are super cool!
あ、最後に歌ったマフィオーサもですね、めちゃめちゃ原曲カッコいいので、ぜひみんな聞いてね！
Ah, the last song "MafiOSA" is also super cool in its original version, so please listen to it!
はい、ということで、今回もあります！周年グッズです！こちら！
Yes! So, we have them again this time! Anniversary goods! Here they are!
急に来る。
That came out of nowhere!
はい。え、今回はですね、なんと、うすた京介先生に描き下ろしていただきました！ありがとうございます！
This time, incredibly, Usuta Kyosuke-sensei drew them for us! Thank you so much!
1つずつ見ていきますかね。
Let's look at them one by one.
え、最初はですね、YB-2、久しぶりに見ました。え、うちのブランドYB-2です。
First up is YB-2, it's been a while since I saw it. Yes, my brand is YB-2.
YB-2の、え、うすた先生バージョンのね、パーカーです。
It's the Usuta-sensei version of the YB-2 hoodie.
裏面に、イラストが来る感じですね。で、胸元にYB-2って入ってて、
The illustration is on the back. And it has "YB-2" on the chest,
腕にね、あの、ころねのモチーフの骨が入っております。
and my motif, bones, on the sleeves.
これめちゃめちゃカッコいいと思うのでね、お楽しみに！
I think this is super cool, so please look forward to it!
はい、続いてこちら。
Next is this.
こちらはですね、あの、パーカーと同じイラストのサコッシュです。
This is a sacoche with the same illustration as the hoodie.
結構ね、なんか、エキスポとかフェスとか、なんかみんなのイベントとかに来るときに、サコッシュ使ってる人結構いたなと思って、
I noticed quite a few people using sacoches when they come to Expos, festivals, or other events,
ころねもサコッシュ出したい！っていうことでサコッシュも出しました。皆さんぜひ使ってください！
so I wanted to make one too! So we made a sacoche. Everyone, please use it!
続いてこちら！
Next up is this!
こちらはですね、えっと、ごめんなさいね。
This is... sorry about that.
え、ラップドッグキャップ！こちらはですね、え、ひこさん先生のデザインで出させていただきました。ありがとうございます。
The Rap Dog Cap! This was designed by Hikosan-sensei. Thank you so much!
え、ここにね、ころねの骨がクロスしてて、横にまたこれYB-2です。これもYB-2なのでね、
Here, my bones are crossed, and on the side, it says "YB-2" again. This is also YB-2,
サコッシュと、サコッシュは、サコッシュもYB-2か。
so the sacoche... wait, the sacoche is also YB-2, right?
パーカーとサコッシュと帽子、え、全部YB-2のブランドでございます。よろしくお願いします。
The hoodie, sacoche, and cap are all under the YB-2 brand. Thank you!
はい、次！
Okay, next!
これはYB-2じゃない、ころねのランダムラバーストラップ！こちらはフカヒレママに描き下ろしてもらいました！ママありがとう！
This is not YB-2! Korone's Random Rubber Strap! This was drawn by Fukahire-mama! Thank you, Mama!
こちらね、4種類ランダムで。
These are random among 4 types.
で、今回ね、ラップの曲が多かったということで、あの、ラップをしてるね、ころねのイラストもありますので、
Since we had a lot of rap songs this time, we have an illustration of Korone rapping.
ぜひ皆さん全種類目指してよかったら買ってみてください。
So if you'd like, try to get all types! Please check them out.
通常衣装と、え、YB-2のジャンプスーツと、グッドドック衣装と、ラップ衣装ですね。よかったら、はい、こちらもご検討ください。
We have the usual outfit, the YB-2 jumpsuit, the Good Dog outfit, and the rap outfit. Please consider getting these!
そして、フルセットの購入特典は、え、うすた先生描き下ろしのポストカード。
And the full set purchase bonus is a postcard drawn by Usuta-sensei!
え、数量限定版もありますけれども、めちゃめちゃ、あの、用意しておりますので、
We also have a limited quantity version, but we have prepared a lot,
あの、急がないで大丈夫です。あの、マジで、結構用意したので、あの、ゆっくりご購入ください。
so no need to rush. Seriously, we prepared plenty, so please take your time with your purchase.
はい、で、通常バージョンはね、箔押しの複製サイン入りとなっております。
Yes, and the regular version comes with a foil-stamped duplicated signature.
はい、ということで、今回のライブもみんなたくさん見てくれてありがとうございました！
So, thank you so much everyone for watching this live show!
以上、Lazy Dog Nightでした！みんな本当いつもありがとうね！
That was Lazy Dog Night! Thank you all so much as always!
また会おう！またねー！
Let's meet again! See ya!
Lazy DoE Night! (INUGAMI KORONE 5th Anniv. LIVE)
Lazy DoE Night! (Inugami Korone 5th Anniversary Live)